

SHEGANASH FATHIMA. M

Contact: +91-7358625856 **E-Mail:** humkobooo@gmail.com

Dynamic executive Offering 6+ years of pioneering success in delivering optimal results and business value in high-growth environments on high-visibility projects in Retail, on network, server, database ordesktop support, virtualization in cloud computing.

EXPERIENCE

- Feb 2021 to Till date with Cognizant Technology Solutions as Escalation Lead (Handling International voice calls)
- Sep 2019 to Feb 2021 with CSS CORP as Technical Support and Sales (Handling international voice calls)
- April 2017 to August 2019 with SUTHERLAND GLOBAL SERVICES as Technical Consultant and Sales (Handling international voice calls)

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES AT COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY

- Answer Phone to respond to customer inquiries and troubleshoot for optimized MAC OSAssist customers with installation / un installation of Parallel.
- Working on multiple OS platforms including Windows, Mac and Linux, cyber securityproducts
- Assist customers with virtual RAM and virtual CPU for each VM machines.
- Virtualization in Cloud computing: In cloud computing, Virtualization facilitates the creation of virtual
 machines and ensures the smooth functioning of multiple operating systems. It also helps create a
 virtual ecosystem for server operating systems and multiple storage
- devices, and it runs multiple operating systems.
- o Assist customers with integration with chef/ Ohai/Docker/vagrant.
- To manage and support all Windows servers including the Operating System
- To recover Windows servers in the event of hardware failure
- To collate and maintain full server inventory
- To review and agree BAU acceptance of change records on Server Management supported environments
- To be Technical Experts in a number of supported Technologies Citrix, Clustering
- o To proactively manage all issues raised as problems and perform root cause analysis where requested
- Perform system health checks both of operating system and supported technologies such as Exchange
- Escalate service enhancement suggestions to the Server Management Proactive Services team
- Provide responsive action to any high priority issue by providing the agreed level of technical cover 7 x 24
- Respond to monitoring alerts and execute reporting of system health and capacity through the use of tools and procedures to ensure compliance with service level agreements and operational standards

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES AT CSS CORP

- Assist customers to Download and Install Windows 10 in MAC OS.
- Answer Phone to respond to customer inquiries and troubleshoot for optimized MAC OS
 - o Assist customers with installation / un installation of Parallel.
- Assist customers with virtual RAM and virtual CPU for each VM machines.
- Assist customers with integration with chef/ Ohai/Docker/vagrant.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES AT SUTHERLAND GLOBAL SERVICES

- Assist customers with any Malware, Virus, and Adware related issues.
- Answer Phone to respond to customer inquiries and troubleshoot for any Malware issues
- Assist customers with installation / un installation of McAfee products.
- Assist customers with product configuration, error messages & / or common issues
- Project a professional company image through phone interaction
- Provide customers with product and service information

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

- M.E.(Applied electronics) from Sathyabama University, Chennai, with 90%
- B.E. (Electronics and Communication Engineering) from Anna University, with 91%

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Windows 2019 AND 2022 Professional
- Selenium and Manual Testing automation tools
- MAC OS
- · MS Office
- Microsoft 365 Platform, including Azure, Exchange, SharePoint, OneDrive and Office
- Strong technical knowledge of network and server operating system
 Experience with support of Windows Operating Systems, SQL Server and Active Directory
- Proven experience in IT infrastructure planning, development, and operations
- VMware, Azure and AWS Server Virtualization
- Enterprise Backup, Replication and Business Continuity and Disaster recover mitigation and response
- Strong understanding of project management principles and practices
- Strong understanding of Helpdesk and Customer Relations Support systems
- Data Security and Cyber Security basics IT infrastructure management functions including configuring, managing, and delivering IT environments using on-site and off-side data centre and cloud infrastructure resources
- Managing software licensing and upgrades
- ITSM: ITIL v4
- Ticketing Tools Managed: Service Now, BMC Remedy, Jira, Cherwell

PUBLICATIONS

• Published a paper in International Journal of IJEST (International Journal for Engineering Science and Technology), titled 'Multi Terrain Surveillance System and Land Mine Detection Robot' which was selected for the International Conference on Computer Modelling and Simulation2012 held in Sanya, China

PUBLICATIONS

• Published a paper in International Journal of IJEST (International Journal for Engineering Science and Technology), titled 'Multi Terrain Surveillance System and Land Mine Detection Robot' which was selected for the International Conference on Computer Modelling and Simulation2012 held in Sanya, China

PERSONAL DETAILS

Marital Status: Single

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Urdu, Arabic and Tamil

Permanent Address: D18, 705, 7th floor, Purva Windermere, Pallikaranai, Chennai-

600100